Guide to the East Carbon High School Audio Visual Collection 1959-1980>
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Pictorial History-Part One 1964/1965, 16mm film Color, no sound, 49:28 minutes (Reel 53)
  - Athletics (Section 7)
    This section contains scenes of a wrestling match, girls cheerleading, and basketball.
  - Biology (Section 8)
    Students sit in biology class, learning how to dissect frogs.
  - Dance Performance (Section 9)
    Dancers in flapper dresses perform 1920's style by doing the Charleston and swinging their beaded necklaces. There are a few other performances like couples dancing and two boys performing in front of microphone.
  - Cheer and Basketball (Section 10)
    It begins with a cheer routine and the flag ceremony. The cheerleaders perform more gymnastic routines before the boys begin playing basketball. Another group of boys dress as the cheerleaders and perform. This is probably a game between the teachers and students. This seen ends with trophies being handed out.
  - Choir, Theater, Lunch (Section 11)
    Male and female students perform in the choir. Then, there is a recording of a play where a family sits in a living room, playing chess and talking. It cuts to students eating in the lunchroom with shots of the lunch ladies and students avoiding eye contact with the camera.
  - Dance (Section 12)
    Two girls announce while couples in fine dance attire walk into the dance area. They pose for the camera and continue walking. There are shots of people dancing, a small pond created in the center of the dance floor, and couples standing around.
  - Cheer and Basketball 2 (Section 13)
    Girls perform a cheerleading routine before a small Viking mascot joins them. It cuts to basketball with East Carbon in white. There are more shots of cheerleaders performing and then once again, back to the basketball game.
- Pictorial History-Part Two 1964/1965, 16mm film Color, no sound, 32:47 minutes (Reel 54)
  - Cheerleading (Section 1)
    Girls bring the flag in before a game. Their performance is blurry but then, it cuts to girls doing the splits and cartwheels. The child Viking mascot peforms with them. Boys can be seen warming up before the game. East Carbon is in white with the opposing team in red.
  - Students (Section 2)
    Male and female stuents sit around outside, talking and playing around with each other.
  - Performance (Section 3)
    This section shows a variety of different people rallying before a game. It cuts to another court where two teams are playing basketball. It cuts back to the cheerleaders performing and having corsages pinned to their jackets. Multiple people are seen receiving an award as well as high school students.
  - Ballet and Play (Section 4)
    A girl in a tutu dances ballet. Multiple fairy tale characters can be seen on stage singing and dancing at various times.
  - Lunchroom (Section 5)
    Older women stand outside lunchroom, milling around, posing for the camera before they are seen sitting in the lunchroom. Different couples stand in front of the camera posing with flowers. There is a quick shot of people playing chess before going back to couples standing around.
  - Men's Athletics (Section 6)
    One hundred or more boys stand in the gym performing calisthenics together as well as running relay races.
  - Trampoline (Section 7)
    Boys jump on trampoline, doing various flips and tricks while other boys stand around spotting them.
  - Women's Athletics (Section 8)
    Girls do calisthenics as well as tumbling sets like cartwheels and back bends.
  - Band (Section 9)
    Male and female students sit on stage playing together.
  - Basketball (Section 10)
    East Carbon, in blue, plays against another team in white.
- Pictorial History 1965/1966, 16mm film Color, no sound, 26:27 minutes (Reel 55)
  - Cheerleading (Section 1)
    Two different cheer groups perform routines.
  - Awards (Section 2)
    The Snow Queen and her attendants are given their sashes. It cuts to dancing on the gym floor with spectators.
  - Students (Section 3)
    It shows cheerleaders in the gym, girls and boys sitting around, and older men talking with a group of students.
  - Wrestling (Section 4)
    A few different wrestling matches are shown at East Carbon.
  - Basketball (Section 5)
    The Vikings play basketball at East Carbon.
  - Women's Gymnastics (Section 6)
    Girls in leotards perform various gymnastic tricks including high beam, floor work, and trampoline.
  - Swimming (Section 7)
    This section is shots of swim practice.
  - Play (Section 8)
    There are multiple different performances including ballet, singing, and dancing. The school band, The Crow and the Birds, perform. There is also a shot of the nativity scene and other christmas themed skits.
  - Personal Development Class (Section 9)
    Girls and boys are shown learning different skills like tying bows and building toy cars. There are shots of christmas decorations. It cuts to a physics class where students are taking notes and laughing. The last scene is of students showing off their sculpture projects which are busts made of clay.
- Pictorial History-Part Two 1965/1966, 16mm film Color, no sound, 38:15 minutes (Reel 56)
  - Students (Section 1)
    Students are dressed in a variety of costumes. There are students sitting around the gym. Then, students are dancing while other students sit around the edge of the gym as couples.
  - Basketball (Section 2)
    The scene opens with basketball players running through a line of cheerleaders. There are shots of the pagent queen and her attendants with their male counterparts. After it cuts to another basketball game.
  - Dance (Section 3)
    This section shows students in the gym doing multiple different kinds of dancing as couples.
  - Basketball 2 (Section 4)
    Girls bring in the flag with cheerleaders doing a routine before the basketball game starts. The East Carbon Vikings are in blue. After the game, the little Viking mascot and cheerleader present awards. Then the cheerleaders pin corsages on themselves.
  - Play (Section 5)
    Some girls put on a play or fashion show that depicts women from every era starting with cave women up to the current period with a variety of different styles like sports wear.
  - Special Event (Section 6)
    Couples are dressed nicely while girls announce and present various corsages. Couples walk down some sort of ramp while people sit around watching. Dancing ensues.
  - Dinner (Section 7)
    Well dressed people sit around eating dinner before it changes to students standing in front of the school. It cuts back to small children being led down a ramp to show off their costume as well as a few other dance performances and fashion items by older girls.
  - Gym-Guys (Section 8)
    Boys run different types of relay races, jump on trampoline, perform acrobatics, and some weightlifting.
  - Gymnastics (Section 9)
    Girls tumble on mats doing dance like routines. They also perform on the high beam.
  - Gym-Girls (Section 10)
    Girls do weird jumprope like movement with sticks. Then they move onto calisthenics.
  - Women's Track (Section 11)
    Girls run short distance races. They also attempt long jumps and pole jumping with other various running exercises.
- Pictorial History-Part One 1966/1967, 16mm film Color, no sound, 55:16 minutes (Reel 57)
  - Football (Section 1)
    At East Carbon, white versus green, play football.
  - Dancing and Fun (Section 2)
    It opens with a luau where people are learning to hula dance. A man performas a dance while accompanied by a ukulele. It cuts to students on stage dressed as detectives while a girl dances. There are other types of skits going on. Boys dress as cheerleaders and perform as well as another pagent queen receiving her sash and crown.
  - Parade (Section 3)
    The parade opens with band and dancers. The pagent queen and her attendants ride in the parade as well as various themed floats. There are cheerleaders and baton twirlers. This is all happening before the football game.
  - Basketball (Section 4)
    At East Carbon, the boys play basketball with shots of people cheering. It cuts to another game with more cheerleaders.
  - Trampoline (Section 5)
    Girls perform different tricks on the trampoline.
  - Cheerleaders (Section 6)
    Multiple different cheering routines are performed for different crowds.
  - Play (Section 7)
    Various costumed students perform skits from witches singing to Batman and Robin.
  - Cheerleaders 2 (Section 8)
    Two different sets of cheerleaders perform different routines before giving out prizes.
  - Play 2 (Section 9)
    This is another set of students messing around on stage performing skits. The quality of film cuts out slightly in this section. There is an overall farm theme happening on stage.
  - Prom (Section 10)
    Couples take pictures and walk down stairs in a grand entrance. They can be seen dancing and then posing with their parents.
  - People (Section 11)
    An older couple stand around as well as young women in bright clothing and hats. Some seem to be posing with their parents.
  - Graduation (Section 12)
    Students in cap and gown pose for pictures. Speeches are made and awards are given out.
  - Construction (Section 13)
    Boys are working on building an A-frame structure.
- Pictorial History Undated, 16mm film Color, no sound, 17:07 minutes, intermittent parts of poor quality (Reel 58)
  This reels shows a variety of different scenes like students walking around, a football game, and other performances. Students are in the classroom, couples are dancing, and there is a fashion show.
- Inventing a Nation-Part I, undated; 16mm film Color, sound (Reel 59)
  The film begins with warbled audio and washed out visuals. It is a film on the birth of America. Alistair Cooke narrates the rise of the American people from the clutches of British reign. He tells the story of the founding fathers and their vital roll in history with the Articles of Confederation. He ties it to current events like the 1970 Senatorial Campaign. This is the first of two parts on America's founding. It is a BBC Television time life film produced by Michael Gill.
- Inventing a Nation-Part II, undated; 16mm film Color, sound, 25:54 minutes (Reel 60)
  This film is the second part to the BBC's film on the invention of America. It continues with Alistair Cooke explaining the importance of the Supreme Court. It explores Thomas Jefferson's history and takes a look at Monticello through the amazing skills that shaped the home.It also speaks of the travel west as an important part of America's history with a look at Daniel Boone and territories in Kentucky and Tennessee.
- Classical Greek: Athens-The Golden Age, undated; 16mm film Color, sound, 26:48 minutes (Reel 61)
  This film is Encyclopedia Britannica's film on Classical Greek, given by Charles Kahn of Columbia University. It explores the major themes and idea of ancient Greece that made it so powerful. Through sculputure and theater, different themes like world order and the city state are illuminated as vital parts of their culture. It gives various historical facts about the acropolis and religious proceedings during that time.
- World War II: 1939-1941, undated; 16mm film Black and white, sound (Reel 62)
  This is an education lecture given by Crane Brinton, Ph.D. from Harvard University. It gives historical background and analysis on Germany's progression across Europe using Blitzkrieg and the Luftwaffe. There are clips from WWII, intermixed with Brinton discussing the implications of certain actions like the attempted German invasion of Russia and the United States entrance into the war.
- Senior Trip to Moab 1963-64, Senior Tea, By Book Cliff Club, Seniors in Caps and Gowns, 1963-1964; 16mm film Color, no sound, 10:51 minutes (Reel 63)
  It begins with a film crew producing some sort of western involving horses, wagons, and fire. The signage ends up saying it is for "Guns of the Rio Conchos" in Moab Utah in 1964. Actors stand around with the students posing for the camera. It cuts to students messing around by the river with girls sitting in the shade or sunbathing. The next scene is of girl students with teacher meeting various people in nice clothing. Students also pose with their parents. The final part of this film is the students in their caps and gowns posing for pictures.
- Homecoming 1965, Bonfire, Assembly, Parade, Game, 16mm film Color, no sound, 6:18 minutes (Reel 64)
  A band performs along with other students. There are shots of homecoming royalty. It cuts to the parade with a variety of Viking themed floats. It cuts to cheerleaders performing on the field and then cuts to the football game.
- Senior Tea May 1965, 16mm film Color, no sound, 8:00 minutes (Reel 65)
  It begins with various performances including a man playing the accordion and girls singing. Other students and their parents stand around taking photos. There are shots of tables set with food and drink for everyone to enjoy. Then, their is a shot with the students in their caps and gowns.
- Senior Tea 1968, May 26, 16mm film Color, no sound, 2:49 minutes (Reel 66)
  Students stand in hallways with their parents before walking into an auditorium.
- Graduation 1968-Part 1, 16mm film Color, no sound, 2:48 minutes (Reel 67)
  Students walk across stage to receive diploma followed by speeches.
- Graduation 1968-Part 2, 16mm film Color, no sound, 3:01 minutes (Reel 68)
  This reel is just shots of students receiving their diplomas.
- "America the Beautiful" student project, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape low volume, poor quality (Reel 69)
  Someone announces the project and then "America the Beautiful" song is played multiple times. It is difficult to hear anything at all.
- Utah Mining Story, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape Begins poorly, restarts (Reel 70)
  This audio gives historical information on the Kennecott and Bingham Canyon Mines. The narrator gives various facts about the mines as well as referencing some visual material.
- Graduation, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape low volume, poor quality (Reel 71)
  The audio is very faint on this reel, but a dialogue between a male and female can be heard. They may be discussing some form of drug and alcohol abuse prevention.
- "A Mother's Love" Poem and Various 1950s Songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape low volume, poor quality, 1:35:00 hours (Reel 72)
  This audiotape containes multiple different motherly references. There is the initial poem and then other orchestral music.
- "Vikings" Basketball Tournament Song and More, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape low volume, poor quality, 1:26:29 hours (Reel 73)
  It begins with multiple renditions of the Viking song. Then, it goes through multiple different ads for cars, grocery stores, and much more. There are other announcements like historical facts about the day, reports, both school and news, and people conversing.